Jim Vinh P Nguyen

566 Ottawa Ave ● Saint Paul, MN 55107 ● Phone: 612-702-0319 ● E-Mail: jimnguyen220@gmail.com ● Github: github.com/jimnguyen220

Full Stack Web Developer with professional experience in the banking industry as a relationship manager and have held previous positions in management and team leader. I am an analytical problem solver and enjoy collaborating with others to find a meaningful solution. My ideal position is to work as software engineer where I can combine skills learned in previous positions with my passion for computer coding.

Experience

Wells Fargo 2008-Present

Premier Banker

Promoted from: Assistant Branch Manager, Service Manager, Small Business Specialist, Licensed Personal Banker (I and II)

- Relationship Manager for 300+ families, collaborating with partners across multiple business channels, creating a unified team for clients in my book of business
- Managed complex customer portfolios, serviced relationships, recommend financial products including investments and credit vehicles to acquire 100% of the customer's business
- Oversaw operations of branch to analyze trends, minimize loss, detect fraud and other fulfillment functions to meet and exceed deadlines and goals
- Leader in affluent segmentation strategy, helping market meet and exceed targets in investment growth and loan production
- Expanded and executed on strategy to acquire new households through community involvement and proactive outsourcing to local businesses in the South Metro Region
- . Repeatedly recognized for top performance and demonstrated ability to quickly learn through fast-track promotions and selection for high-priority initiatives

T-Mobile 2005-2008

Senior Retail Sales Associate

- Appointed to floor leader position to coach and develop skills of new members on the sales team
- Provided support for SMTP, and general troubleshooting for mobile devices
- Consistently ranked in top 10% of division in sales for Net New sales and Acquisition Rate Per Units for Minneapolis-Twin Cities Market

Epicor Software 2006-2007

Business Development Representative

- Worked with multiple levels of management and C-Level executives to build relationships and find new opportunities for Territory Managers
- · Gained familiarity with ERP and POS software

State of MN - Como Community Unit

2004-2006

Mental Health Programs Assistant

- Participated as a team member in the treatment for chronically Mentally III, and Chemically Dependent patients and clients
- Accurate documentation of case notes to effectively coordinate with other team members and facilitate effective care

Education

University of MN 2021

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

Hamline University 2006

Bachelor of Arts

Skills and Professional Licenses

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDV, Express, ReactJS, Series 7, Series 66, Life and Variable Annuities Licensure